Laurence W. "Bill" Lane, Jr. papers, circa 1953-2010 M1811
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- 75th Anniversary of Sunset 1898-1973: Donnelly Mailing List (Carton 7, Folder 15)
- 75th Anniversary of Sunset 1898-1973: Congratulatory Letters (Carton 7, Folder 16)
- 80th Anniversary of Sunset 1978: [Miscellaneous] (Carton 7, Folder 17)
- Audio Cassettes [1 of 2]: KABC, Michael Jackson Show, Bill Lane, 50th Anniv Talk, 6/23/78 (2 copies, one labeled 6/23/79); Bill Lane, Denver Story, 10/2/1984; Michael Jackson: Yosemite, 5/9/85, KABC Radio (2 copies). (Carton 7, Folder 18)
- Audio Cassettes [2 of 2]: "Who's In Charge?", the Barbara Simpson Show, KGO-AM San Francisco, 2/21/89 (2 copies); "Bill Lane - Sunset Magazine", News, KOA-AM/Denver 10/25/1989; "Bill Lane - Sunset Magazine," Bill Gallagher Show, KXL-AM/Portland, 5/16/1990; Joe Willaimson Interview, with Jack McKinnon, Sunset Gardens, 8/2/1990. (Carton 7, Folder 19)
- Heart of the Golden State, California State Parks Foundation, 10/4/1995 dub, VHS, 8:00 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Heart of the Golden State, California State Parks Foundation, 2/28/97 - new, dub (2 copies), VHS, 8:42 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Looking in on Sunset, revised, Sunset Publishing, 1985 (2 copies), VHS, 15:02 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Looking in on Sunset, revised, Sunset Publishing, 16/93 (2 copies), VHS, 15:02 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Looking in on Sunset, Wallace Stegner, with Bill Lane as Host (revised, 12/29/2004) (2 copies), VHS (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Getting to Know Our Readers Even Better; Introduction by Bill Lane, Publisher Sunset Magazine, 1989 (2 copies) (Box 8, Folder 6)
- A Fireside Chat With Bill Lane and a Few of His Friends, VHS (Box 8, Folder 7)
- A Fireside Chat With Bill Lane - Revisited Upon Return From Australia, 1989, VHS (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Tough Customers: How to Sell 'Em in the West; Sunset Magazine, 1988, VHS, 23:00 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- A Connecticut Yankee in Sunset's West - Marketing 1990 Sunset Films, 1990, VHS, 25:00 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- The Great Western Adventure (Marketing '89), Sunset Film and Television, VHS, 24:00 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- The Great Western Adventure (Marketing '89), Sunset Film and Television, VHS, 23:00 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- California's Gold: Firefall, hosted by Huell Howser, Show #706, VHS (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Bill Lane Tribute: A Passion for Parks, 3/20/95, National Parks and Conservation Assn, VHS, 12:40 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- The Vision of Bill Mott, KRON - TV, VHS (Box 9, Folder 7)
- The Global Village Revisited, 5/1993, Sunwest Media (3 copies), VHS, 25:00 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Spirit of Australia Award: Ambassador L.W. "Bill" Lane, Jr., Australian/American Chamber of Commerce (2 copies), VHS (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Bill Lane Jr. - Sunset Magazine/Lane Publishing, 7/31/2000; SVCC's Newswatch with Mike Cobb, VHS, 29:04 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- The PATA Story: Points of Vision (3 copies), VHS, 18:20 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Yosemite Fund Presentation, Sunset Films and Television, VHS, 06:07 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- The Yosemite Fund: Providing for Yosemite's Future (may be same as above), VHS (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Succession Transitions in Family Business, Temoin Production, 4, 1996, VHS, 26:20 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- The American West with Bill Lane: Importances and Differences of Western America and the Pacific Basin, SRI International, 1981 (2 copies), VHS (Box 10, Folder 5)
- What's So Great About the Bloomin' West?, Sunset Fims and Television, 1969, VHS (Box 10, Folder 6)
- And Now For The News, Sunset Films and Television, 1977, VHS (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Speaking of Menlo Park: Bill Lane, VHS (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Menlo Park Shop Talk I, Sunset Films and Telelvision, VHS, 18:00 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Bill Lane/Sunset Magazine, Sun Up San Diego, KFMB-TV, San Diego, 7/25/1989, VHS, 03:41 (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Making Future History: A Campaign for the Leland Stanford Mansion Restoration, 8/93 (2 copies), VHS, 15:52 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Celebrate a Legacy in Tourism: A Tribute to Bill and Jean Lane, University of Hawai'I Foundation, 9/23/03, VHS, 08:35 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Celebrate a Legacy in Tourism: Governor Ariyoshi Tribute, 11/12/2002, VHS (Box 11, Folder 3)
- 2000 Lane Family Lecture, Todd Auditorium, 10/12/2000, VHS (Box 11, Folder 4)
- 2004 Lane Family Lecture: Ecology vs. Economy?Setting the Real Bottom Line, David Suzuki, 10/13/2004, VHS (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Coastal Clash, KQED Public Television Production, VHS, 56:46 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Mineral Policy Center, NBC Nightly News: Fleecing of America, VHS (Box 11, Folder 7)
- "Sunday on Seven" Sunset Show, May 1998, VHS (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Charlie Rose Show with Tom Brokaw, lauding "The Greatest Generation," 12/14/1998, VHS (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Elsa Knowles Interview, Edited Comments (Copy), VHS (Box 11, Folder 10)
- (Box 11, Folder 11)
- Copies of videotapes in previous boxes, VHS (Box 12)
- First Citizen Banquet Salem Oregon Talk (Carton 13, Folder 1)
- Dow Jones National Management Conference 11/28/1967 (Carton 13, Folder 2)
- District 4 California Park and Recreation Society (West Bay Area) 10/19/1967 (Carton 13, Folder 3)
- 47th Annual Redwood Empire Assn. Convention, 9/28/1967 (Carton 13, Folder 4)
- Menlo Park Lions Club, 10/16/1967 (Carton 13, Folder 5)
- "Is The West All It's Cracked Up To Be", San Diego Ad Club 9/13/1967 (Carton 13, Folder 6)
- National Home Fashion League Los Angeles Chapter, 7/19/1967 (Carton 13, Folder 7)
- Vacaville Rotary Club, March 23, 1967 (Carton 13, Folder 8)
- Better Business Bureau of Spokane WA, Jan 23, 1967 (Carton 13, Folder 9)
- American Hotel and Motel Association Convention Conservation Panel, 12/1/1966 (Carton 13, Folder 10)
- Associated Press Managing Press Editors at Hotel del Coronado, Nov. 16,1966 (Carton 13, Folder 11)
- "How Deep Is The Western Well": Sales Promotion Executives Assoc. in Las Vegas, May 16, 1966 (Carton 13, Folder 12)
- East Bay Lawyers' Wives, Oakland CA, June 2, 1966 (Carton 13, Folder 13)
- California Avocado Advisory Board, San Diego area, May 19, 1966 (Carton 13, Folder 14)
- Pacific Coast Electric Association, San Diego, CA, May 19, 1966 (Carton 13, Folder 15)
- Pot and Kettle Club Convention, Hoberg's, june 29, 1966 (Carton 13, Folder 16)
- Seafare-Rotary Club, Seattle WA, 8/3/1966 (Carton 13, Folder 17)
- Keep America Beautiful, San Francisco, CA 9/30/1966 (Carton 13, Folder 18)
- P.U.A.A. [Public Utitlities Advertising Assn.], Phoenix, AZ, 5/5/1966 (Carton 13, Folder 19)
- National Airlines Sales Meeting, Jack Tar Hotel, 4/26/1966 (Carton 13, Folder 20)
- Pacific Coast Gas Assn. (Seattle) 9/8/1965 (Carton 13, Folder 21)
- American Photoengravers Speech, Los Angeles, 9/20/1965 (Carton 13, Folder 22)
- S.A.T.O. [South American travel Organization], Miami, FL, 10/29/1965 (Carton 13, Folder 23)
- Seattle and Portland Ad Club talk: Does It Pay to be Honest?, 4/12-13/1966 (Carton 13, Folder 24)
- WACTI (Western America Convention and Travel Institute), Seattle, 6/10/1965 (Carton 13, Folder 25)
- Western Red Cedar Lumber Assn (Western Wood Products Assn.), Qualicum Beach, B.C., 6/11/1965 (Carton 13, Folder 26)
- American Assoc. of Nurserymen, Inc., Portland, OR, 7/21/1965 (Carton 13, Folder 27)
- Advertising Assoc. of the West (AAW), Honolulu, 6/30/1965 (Carton 13, Folder 28)
- Just A Little Bit of Tourism, San Diego C and VB [Convention and Vacation Bureau], 1965 (Carton 13, Folder 29)
- Fresno State, 1965 (Carton 13, Folder 30)
- Challenge of Change, ABC, 1965 (Carton 13, Folder 31)
- Magazine Industry Seminar, Harvard Graduate School of Business, July 20, 1964 (Carton 13, Folder 32)
- Materials for Speeches (General) [1 of 2] (Carton 13, Folder 33)
- Conservation (Carton 13, Folder 34)
- Challenge in the Pacific: Plenary Session Second Pacific Area Travel Conference, Honolulu, 3/13/1953 (Carton 13, Folder 35)
- Integrity [notes scribbled on scrap of paper] (Carton 13, Folder 36)
- Is Hawaii Breaking It's Promise, 6/26/1972 (Carton 14, Folder 1)
- 1972 Sunset Hawaii Reader Survey: Returned Questionnaires [1 of 3] (Carton 14, Folder 2)
- 1972 Sunset Hawaii Reader Survey: Returned Questionnaires [2 of 3] (Carton 14, Folder 3)
- 1972 Sunset Hawaii Reader Survey: Returned Questionnaires [3 of 3] (Carton 14, Folder 4)
- National Parks Centennial Commission Opening Press Statement (Carton 14, Folder 5)
- Bring Me Men to Match My Mountains: 54th DMAA Conference, Fairmont Hotel, 9/13/1971 (Carton 14, Folder 6)
- Tourism: California's Opportunity Industry, 1st Official California Tourism Conference, 6/15/1971 (Carton 14, Folder 7)
- Tourism (Carton 14, Folder 8)
- May 1971 FES [Floyd E. Shaw] Reader Surveys: Orinda (Carton 14, Folder 9)
- May 1971 FES [Floyd E. Shaw] Reader Surveys: San Rafael (Carton 14, Folder 10)
- May 1971 FES [Floyd E. Shaw] Reader Surveys: Foster City (Carton 14, Folder 11)
- Tourism: Opportunity with Responsibility, May 1971 (Carton 14, Folder 12)
- Oregon Travel Industry Conference, II, Speech by Governor John McCall, 4/14/1971 (Carton 14, Folder 13)
- Los Banos Chamber of Commerce, Dec 7, 1970 (Carton 14, Folder 14)
- Reno Executive Club, Nov. 30, 1970 (Carton 14, Folder 15)
- "The Challenge of Change," ABC [Audit Bureau of Circulations] Meeting, October 21, 1970 (Carton 14, Folder 16)
- Western Candy Conference, Monterey, February, 1970 (Carton 14, Folder 17)
- "Environment is Everbody's Thing," Santa Barbara Chamber of Conference, January 1970 (Carton 14, Folder 18)
- Governor's Conference on California's Changing Environment, Nov 17-18, 1969 (Carton 14, Folder 19)
- People and Water Panel: Governor's Conference on California's Changing Environment, Nov 17-18, 1969 (Carton 14, Folder 20)
- People and Water Panel: Not In Transcript or partially in Transcript (Carton 14, Folder 21)
- People and Water Panel: Prepared Speeches Alreadiy In Transcript (Carton 14, Folder 22)
- "The West and It's Opportunities," Nevada Governor's Conference, November, 1969 (Carton 14, Folder 23)
- "The Sunset Story, or, Don't Kill the Fish," Newcomen Society Dinner, May 15, 1969 (Carton 14, Folder 24)
- Coronado Rotary Club, 5/7/1969 (Carton 14, Folder 25)
- Daisy Awards, Banquet, May 7, 1969 (Carton 14, Folder 26)
- Architectural Aluminum Maunfacturers Assn, April 23, 1969 (Carton 14, Folder 27)
- Advertising Club of LA, 3/12/1969 (Carton 14, Folder 28)
- Council of California Growers, 2/26/1969 (Carton 14, Folder 29)
- "The Promise of Hawaii," Institute of Hawaii, 1/8/1969 (Carton 14, Folder 30)
- Burlingame Rotary Club Talk, 12/11/1968 (Carton 14, Folder 31)
- "Fresh Ideas Are All Around Us," National Home Fashions League, 1968 (Carton 14, Folder 32)
- San Francisco Rotary Club Talk, October 8, 1968 (Carton 14, Folder 33)
- "Where Do We Go From Here?", San Francisco Rotary Club, 10/1/1968 (Carton 15, Folder 1)
- AAF (American Advertising Federation) Portland Convention, July 7-11, 1968 (Carton 15, Folder 2)
- Wine Institute, 6/7/1968 (Carton 15, Folder 3)
- San Diego Dairy Luncheon Talk, 6/4/1968 (Carton 15, Folder 4)
- Talk to Western Association of Food Chains (Carton 15, Folder 5)
- Talk to International Aviation, 5/21/1968 (Carton 15, Folder 6)
- Liberal Arts Series - Vandenberg Air Force Base Speech, 5/1/1968 (Carton 15, Folder 7)
- Talk to Salt Lake City Ad Club, 3/27/1968 (Carton 15, Folder 8)
- Talk to Oakland Chamber of Commerce, 3/12/1968 (Carton 15, Folder 9)
- Cultural Heritage Conservation Seminar, 7/21/1968 (Carton 15, Folder 10)
- Cultural Heritage Conservation Seminar Talk, LWL Jr., 7/22/1968 (Carton 15, Folder 11)
- Keynote Address - International Tourism Workshop - Seattle, Red Lion Inn/Sea Tac [1981?]; audiotape (Carton 15, Folder 12)
- Tourism: People-To-People Force for Peace, Washington D.C., May 29, 1980 (Carton 15, Folder 13)
- GMA (Grocery Manufacturers of America) Talk, July 28, 1980 (Carton 15, Folder 14)
- Seminar of the Century: Vancouver B.C. Talk November 24, 1980 [Some photos, negatives] (Carton 15, Folder 15)
- Resort Committee of the American Hotel Assn., Salishan Hotel, Oregon, 9/16-20/1979 (Carton 15, Folder 16)
- JCA (Japan - California Association) "The Western Business Climate," 1978 (Carton 15, Folder 17)
- Watching the West for Lifestyle: General Electric Speech, 10/1/1978 (Carton 15, Folder 18)
- Futura Caution AAAA (American Association of Advertising Agencies), Del Monte 10/11/1976 (Carton 15, Folder 19)
- "Everything Coming Up Roses?", Juneau, 1975 (Carton 15, Folder 20)
- "Yes Mr. Cole, I Would," HJF (Henry Johnson Fisher) Award, 1974 (Carton 15, Folder 21)
- "Magazines in the Total Media Mix," Magazine Day Luncheon, LA, 10/24/1973 (Carton 15, Folder 22)
- "Tourism," PBEC (Pacific Basin Economic Council) Tour, 1973 (Carton 15, Folder 23)
- Speeches, 1973 [photographs] (Carton 15, Folder 24)
- Atlanta MAR (Magazine Advertisers Representatives of the South) Talk, 11/11/1974 (Carton 15, Folder 25)
- Magazine Day in San Francisco, 11/6/1974 (Carton 15, Folder 26)
- Vinegar Institute Talk, St Francis Hotel, 1/25/1973 (Carton 15, Folder 27)
- Hughes Air West, 1/23/1973 (Carton 15, Folder 28)
- San Mateo County Convention and Visitors Bureau - First Annual Luncheon, 3/23/1973 (Carton 15, Folder 29)
- "National Parks, Our Biggest Arboretum," 1972 (Carton 15, Folder 30)
- "PATA's Rich Heritage: Critical for a Sound Future," 27th Annual Conference, New Delhi, India, 1/25/1978 (Carton 15, Folder 31)
- Stanford Business School - San Francisco Club, 11/28/1972 [no speech/talk, correspondence] (Carton 16, Folder 1)
- San Francisco Rotary Club Talk, 10/10/1972 (Carton 16, Folder 2)
- Lakeside Talk, 7/23/1972 (Carton 16, Folder 3)
- Monterey Ad Club, La Playa Hotel, 1972 (Carton 16, Folder 4)
- T.I.E. Conference, 6/16/1972 (Carton 16, Folder 5)
- California Chamber of Commerce (published in Pacific Business),4/13/1972 (Carton 16, Folder 6)
- SMEA April 3, 1972 (Carton 16, Folder 7)
- National Parks: Guardians of our heritage, Fresno, Chamber of Commerce, March24, 1972 (Carton 16, Folder 8)
- PATA 1979 Korea (Carton 16, Folder 9)
- 1980 Paris Board Meeting (PATA Also Oberamagau) (Carton 16, Folder 10)
- PATA Manila Lane Itinerary (Carton 16, Folder 11)
- Miscellaneous (Marcos, Aspiras, Steinberg, Mansfield) (Carton 16, Folder 12)
- U.S. Night Manila (Wine etc.) (Carton 16, Folder 13)
- A-V Presentation (Carton 16, Folder 14)
- New Members??. (Carton 16, Folder 15)
- 1981 Accomodations (Carton 16, Folder 16)
- Tours (Carton 16, Folder 17)
- Pacific Heritage Society (Carton 16, Folder 18)
- Gerald R. Ford, JR. (Carton 16, Folder 19)
- President James E. Carter (Carton 16, Folder 20)
- Carlos Romulo (Carton 16, Folder 21)
- Sheik Ahmad Zaki Yamani (Carton 16, Folder 22)
- James Michener (Carton 16, Folder 23)
- Walter Cronkite (Carton 16, Folder 24)
- Inouye Correspondence (Carton 16, Folder 25)
- Wells Fargo (Carton 16, Folder 26)
- Duncan Hamilton (Carton 16, Folder 27)
- Ken Chamberlain (Carton 16, Folder 28)
- Walter Cronkite (Carton 16, Folder 29)
- Lars Lindblad (Carton 16, Folder 30)
- Miguel Aleman (Carton 16, Folder 31)
- Lim Chin Beng (Carton 16, Folder 32)
- Kurt Waldheim (Carton 16, Folder 33)
- Richard Ferris (Carton 16, Folder 34)
- Lee Kwan Yew (Carton 16, Folder 35)
- Gautam Khanna (Carton 16, Folder 36)
- Weldon B. Gibson" (Carton 16, Folder 37)
- "Meeting Summaries" (Carton 16, Folder 38)
- PATA Conference March 10,1981, Los Angeles, CA (Carton 16, Folder 39)
- PATA Mailing III (Carton 16, Folder 40)
- PATA Mailing IV (Carton 16, Folder 41)
- PATA V (Carton 16, Folder 42)
- PATA '81 Mailing I (Carton 16, Folder 43)
- PATA '81 Mailing II (Carton 16, Folder 44)
- Horizon La Editorial (Carton 16, Folder 45)
- Editorial for 10th Anniv. Of Travel Age West by Bill Lane Tourism Facing Critical Years (Carton 16, Folder 46)
- PATA '81 Related Advertising (Carton 16, Folder 47)
- Press (Carton 16, Folder 48)
- "PATA 1981 Conference Program" (Carton 16, Folder 49)
- Program (Carton 16, Folder 50)
- PATA Board Meeting February 16-20, 1981 (Carton 16, Folder 51)
- Customs (Carton 16, Folder 52)
- Board of Directors Dinner Party Monday, February 16, 1981 (Carton 16, Folder 53)
- Guam Lunch- Monday, February 16 (Carton 16, Folder 54)
- Opening Ceremony, Feb. 18 Wednesday, 1981 (Carton 16, Folder 55)
- Pionneers Dinner February 23,1981 (Carton 16, Folder 56)
- SFC & UB Reception Sunday, February 22, 1981 (Carton 17, Folder 1)
- "PATA 1981 Workshop Program (Carton 17, Folder 2)
- March Fong Eu (Carton 17, Folder 3)
- Diane Feinstein (Carton 17, Folder 4)
- Chairman's Dinner Program (Carton 17, Folder 5)
- Chairman's Dinner Wed. Feb. 18, 1981 (Carton 17, Folder 6)
- PATA '81 Sunset Tour Sat. Feb. 21, 1981 (Carton 17, Folder 7)
- Ainslie- Heritage Seminar Sunday, February 22, 1981 (Carton 17, Folder 8)
- Lane Publishing Co. Funds to PATA (Carton 17, Folder 9)
- Articles (Carton 17, Folder 10)
- PATA Aerogram Dedication December 29, 1980 (Carton 17, Folder 11)
- Closing Ceremonies February 24, 1981 (Carton 17, Folder 12)
- Credit to Contributors (Carton 17, Folder 13)
- Misc. (Ranston-Brademas ) Warner (Carton 17, Folder 14)
- Fund Raising (Carton 17, Folder 15)
- A.W. Clausen (Carton 17, Folder 16)
- "B of a Lunch" Mon. Feb. 23, 1981 (Carton 17, Folder 17)
- Ernie Ford (Carton 17, Folder 18)
- "Chevron USA Dinner Tues. Feb. 24" (Carton 17, Folder 19)
- Peter Dailey (Carton 17, Folder 20)
- "PATA 1981 Hit list" (Carton 17, Folder 21)
- PATA '81 Gifts (Carton 17, Folder 22)
- Aleman Photos (Carton 17, Folder 23)